（走过的路）
你们要面对现实 承担起你们的责任
You're gonna suck it up, accept your responsibilities,
扮演好你们命中注定的角色
and play the roles that destiny has chosen for you.
你就是那皮囊 米迦勒的皮囊
You're the vessel. Michael's vessel.
我的答案是 不同意
The answer's no.
- 你知道我是谁 - 路西法
- You know who I am. - Lucifer.
萨姆 就是你 你就是我的皮囊
You're the one, Sam. You're my vessel.
这绝对不可能
That'll never happen.
嗨 莉莎 情况真的会很糟
Hi, Lisa. Things are about to get really bad.
- 不管你打算干什么 别去 - 我必须去
- Whatever you're thinking of doing, don't do it. - I have to.
那个关路西法的牢笼
The cage you sprung Lucifer from …
你们可以再把他扔回去
You can shove his ass back in.
想要打开牢笼
The key to the cage …
需要天启四骑士手上的四枚戒指
four rings from the horsemen.
- 这是谁 - 我们的弟弟
- Who is it? - That's our brother.
- 亚当不见了是什么意思 - 天使带走了他
- What do you mean Adam is gone? - The angels took him.
或许他们放弃你了 迪恩
Maybe they're moving on from you, Dean.
亚当没事吧
Think Adam's okay?
不
No.
拿不准
Doubt it.
如果你们引诱路西法到牢笼前 然后我跳进去呢
What if you guys lead the devil to the edge and I jump in?
你们俩个傻瓜是不是想气死我啊
Are you idjits trying to kill me?!
你必须让你弟弟
You're going to let your brother.
纵身跳入那个火坑中
jump right into that fiery pit.
你究竟在害怕什么
What exactly are you afraid of?
是怕失败
Losing?
还是害怕失去你弟弟
Or losing your brother?
1967年4月21日
On April 21, 1967,
第一亿辆通用牌汽车在简斯维尔的工厂
The 100 millionth GM vehicle rolled off the line.
生产下线
at the plant in Janesville …
这是一辆蓝色双门的卡普里斯
A blue two-door Caprice.
为此举行了一场盛大的典礼 大家纷纷演讲
There was a big ceremony, speeches.
甚至连副州长都出席了
The lieutenant governor even showed up.
三天之后 另一辆车在同一生产线上下线
Three days later, another car rolled off that same line.
她并没有引起外界过多的关注
No one gave two craps about her.
他们真是没眼光
But they should have.
因为这辆1967年款的雪佛兰英帕拉
Because this 1967 Chevrolet Impala.
将会成为世上最重要的车…
would turn out to be the most important car …
不 是最重要的物体
No, the most important object …
成为整个宇宙的重中之重
in pretty much the whole universe.
她的第一任车主是赛尔·莫里亚蒂
She was first owned by Sal Moriarty,
他是个曾离过两次婚
An alcoholic with two ex-wives.
并患有三条动脉阻塞的酒鬼
and three blocked arteries.
周末时 他会驱车四处 向穷人们分发圣经
On weekends, he'd drive around giving bibles to the poor.
「让世人了解最终末日」
"Gettin' folks right for judgment day."
他是这么说的
that's what he said.
萨姆和迪恩完全不知道这些
Sam and Dean don't know any of this,
但若他们知道 我保证他们会微笑的
but if they did, I bet they'd smile.
赛尔死后 她就被停在一个地处劳伦斯
After Sal died, she ended up at Rainbow Motors,
叫做「彩虹汽车」的二手车店
A used-car lot in Lawrence,
一个年轻的陆战队员心血来潮买下了她
where a young marine bought her on impulse.
因为他听取了某个朋友的小小建议
That is, after a little advice from a friend.
故事就是从那里开始的
I guess that's where this story begins.
并且将在这里结束
And here's where it ends.
迪恩
Dean?
怎么了
What's going on?
我同意了
I'm in.
同意啥
In with…?
「和路西法对对碰」这事儿
The whole "Up with Satan" Thing.
我同意了
I'm on board.
你要让我对路西法说同意
You're gonna let me say yes?
不 是这样的
No. That's the thing.
我无法命令你去做什么
It's not on me to let you do anything.
你已经长大了 而且长得过大了
You're a grown … well, overgrown … man.
如果你想这么做 我会支持你
If this is what you want, I'll back your play.
我完全没想到你会这么说
That's the last thing I thought you'd ever say.
谁说不是
Might be.
我不想骗你
I'm not gonna lie to you, though.
这可完全违背了我的性格
It goes against every fiber I got.
事实上
I mean, truth is…
照顾你什么的
…You know, watching out for you…
就好像是我的工作一样
It's kinda been my job, you know?
但那不只是个工作
But more than that, it's…
我就是这样的一个人
It's kinda who I am.
萨姆 你不再是个孩子了
You're not a kid anymore, Sam,
我不能一直把你当小孩子一样对待
And I can't keep treating you like one.
可能我也需要再成熟点了
Maybe I got to grow up a little, too.
我不知道我们是否有获胜的机会
I don't know if we got a snowball's chance.
但是
But…
但我知道如果有人能做到的话
But I do know that if anybody can do it…
那人就是你
It's you.
谢谢
Thank you.
如果你想这么做…
If this is what you want…
你真的想这么做吗
Is this really what you want?
是我把他放出来的
I let him out.
我必须再把他关回去
I got to put him back in.
好
Okay.
那就这么定了
That's it, then.
[邪恶力量 第5季第22集]
还是不习惯你站着跟我说话
I still can't get used to you at eye level.
我说对了吗
So, was I right?
一如既往的对了 尤达大师
As always, Yoda.
如你所说 里面有两个恶魔小喽啰
Two stunt demons inside, just like you said.
拿到血了吗
Did you get it?
嗯 全是萨姆的「动力果汁」
Yeah, all the "Go juice" Sammy can drink.
你还好吧
You okay?
不太好
Not really.
有什么发现
What do you got?
所获不多 你看这些像是预兆吗
Not much. These look like omens to you?
佛罗里达的飓风
Cyclone in Florida,
底特律的突然降温 洛杉矶的大火
Temperature drop in Detroit, Wildfires in l.A.
等等 底特律怎么了
Wait. What about Detroit?
气温骤降了20度
Temp's dropped about 20 degrees,
但只发生在市中心半径五个街区的范围内
but only in a five-block radius of downtown motown.
就是这儿了
That's the one.
恶魔在底特律
Devil's in Detroit.
真的
Really?
就预兆而言
As far as foreboding goes,
这种程度可太轻了
It's a little light in the loafers.
你确定吗
You sure?
我确定
Yeah, I'm sure.
睡相真可爱 像个小天使对吧
Aw. Ain't he a little angel?
天使可不睡觉
Angels don't sleep.
萨姆 我对这事有种不好的预感
Sam, I got a bad feeling about this.
你要是有好的预感才怪了
Well, you'd be nuts to have a good feeling about it.
你知道我的意思
You know what I mean.
底特律
Detroit.
他一直说 他会在底特律占有你的身体
He always said he'd jump your bones in Detroit.
现在我们来了
Here we are.
我们来了
知道吗 也许这是他在热烈欢迎你
Maybe this is him rolling out the red carpet, you know?
也许他知道一些我们不知道的事
Maybe he knows something that we don't.
迪恩 他肯定知道一大票我们不知道的事
Dean, I'm sure he knows a buttload we don't.
我们只能希望他不知道戒指的事了
We just got to hope he doesn't know about the rings.
对了…
Hey, um…
说到这个
On the subject,
有件事我得告诉你
There's something I got to talk to you about.
什么事
What?
如果事情按我们预想的方向发展
This thing goes our way.
我要跳进那个笼子里
And I…triple lindy into that box…
你知道我是有去无回吧
…Y-you know I'm not coming back.
知道 我很清楚
Yeah, I'm aware.
那你得答应我一件事
So you got to promise me something.
好 尽管说吧
Okay. Yeah. Anything.
你得发誓不会试着救我回来
You got to promise not to try to bring me back.
什么
What?
不 这我可不干
No, I didn't sign up for that.
迪恩
Dean …
你把我的旅行弄得像绝唱似的
Your hell is gonna make my tour look like graceland.
你还想让我袖手旁观
Y-you want me just to sit by and do nothing?
一旦牢笼关上 你决不能再去碰它
Once the cage is shut, you can't go poking at it, Dean.
这太冒险了
It's too risky.
不不不
No, no, no, no, no.
就好像我会让你烂在那不管似的
As if I'm just gonna let you rot in there.
没错 就是这样 你别无选择
Yeah, you are. You don't have a choice.
你不能要求我这么做
You can't ask me to do this.
抱歉 迪恩 你必须如此
I'm sorry, Dean. You have to.
不去救你 那我要做些什么
So then what am I supposed to do?
去找莉莎
You go find Lisa.
向上帝祷告让她接纳你
You pray to god she's dumb enough to take you in,
然后你们可以吃烤肉 踢球赛
And you … you have barbecues and go to football games.
你要过正常且简单有序的生活 迪恩
You go live some normal, apple-pie life, Dean.
答应我
Promise me.
（密歇根州 底特律）
是恶魔
Demons.
起码有两打
At least two dozen of them.
你是对的 有事要发生了
You were right … something's up.
不只如此
More than something.
他在这里 我知道
He's here. I know it.
再见 孩子
I'll see ya around, kid.
再见
See ya around.
被他附身之后
He gets in…
你要拼命与他对抗 明白吗
You fight him tooth and nail, you understand?
要一直抗争 丝毫不能放松
Keep swingin'. Don't give an inch.
明白
Yes, sir.
照顾好他们 行吗
Take care of these guys, okay?
他们不可能「好」的
That's not possible.
那就假装迁就我一下
Then humor me.
哦 我该说谎的
Oh. I was supposed to lie.
当然 他们会没事的 我…
Sure. They'll be fine. I …
得得…你还是…别说了
Just … just stop…Talking.
别看行吗
You mind not watching this?
好了
Okay.
我们走吧
Let's go.
来啊
All right!
我们来了 狗杂种们
We're here, you sons of bitches!
放马过来
Come and get it!
伙计们
Hey, guys.
你们老爸在家吗
Is your father home?
你们好
Hey, guys.
谢谢你们来看我
So nice of you to drop in.
这辆英帕拉的零件
The Impala, of course,
自然与其它车并无不同
has all the things other cars have…
还有些其它车上没有的装备
And a few things they don't.
但这些都不重要
But none of that stuff's important.
重要的是一些小东西
This is the stuff that's important.
萨姆塞进烟灰盒里的人偶大兵
The army man that Sam crammed in the ashtray…
如今还在那里
It's still stuck there.
迪恩塞进出风口的积木
The legos that Dean shoved into the vents…
直到今天 暖风一开就能听见它们噼啪作响
To this day, heat comes on and they can hear 'em rattle.
正是这些小东西让这辆车变得完整
These are the things that make the car theirs…
变得真正属于他们
Really theirs.
即便是迪恩在车散架之后进行整体大修
Even when Dean rebuilt her from the ground up,
仍然没有把这些小东西取出去
he made sure all these little things stayed,
因为这些瑕疵正是她的美丽所在
'cause it's the blemishes that make her beautiful.
路西法不知道他们开什么车
The devil doesn't know or care.
他也不在乎
what kind of car the boys drive.
抱歉可能有点儿冷
Sorry if it's a bit chilly.
大部分人都以为我喜欢熊熊烈焰
Most people think I burn hot.
事实上恰恰相反
It's actually quite the opposite.
好吧 我会通知媒体的
Well, I'll alert the media.
伙计们 帮我解释一下
Help me understand something, guys.
我是说 难道你们不觉得
I mean, stomping through my front door.
闯进我家有点儿自取灭亡吗
Is…A tad suicidal, don't you think?
我们不是来和你对抗的
We're not here to fight you.
不是吗
No?
那是来做什么的
Then why are you?
我要同意你附身
I want to say "Yes."
你说什么
Excuse me?
喝了不少阿华田呐
Chock-full of ovaltine, are we?
你听到我说的了
You heard me.
我同意
Yes.
你是认真的
You're serious.
听着 审判日的降临无法阻挡
Look, Judgment Day's a runaway train.
我们想通了 我们只求免灾
We get it now. We just want off.
意思是
Meaning?
世纪交易
Deal of the century.
我同意你附身 条件是一切结束之后
I give you a free ride, but when it's all over,
我俩都要活着 我们的父母也要复活
I live, he lives, you bring our parents back…
算了 咱别演肥皂剧了行么
Okay, can we please drop the telenovela?
我知道戒指在你们手里 萨姆
I know you have the rings, Sam.
我不知道你在说什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
天启四骑士的戒指
The Horsemen's rings?
打开我牢笼的钥匙
The magic keys to my cage?
有印象吗
Ring a bell?
拜托了萨姆 我从没骗过你
Come on, Sam. I've never lied to you.
你至少也应该给我同样的尊重
You could at least pay me the same respect.
没关系 我不生气
It's okay. I'm not mad.
在你的意识里较量一番
A wrestling match inside your noggin…
我喜欢这主意
I like the idea.
只有你我 一局定胜负 不许耍诈
Just you and me, one round, no tricks.
要是你赢了 就跳回牢笼
You win, you jump in the hole.
要是我赢了
I win…
那我就赢了
Well, then I win.
萨姆 意下如何
What do you say, Sam?
一把金提琴 赌你的灵魂
A fiddle of gold against your soul.
我会比你强
says I'm better than you-ou.
他已经知道了 但是没有关系
So he knows. Doesn't change anything.
萨姆
Sam.
- 我们别无选择 - 别
- We don't have any other choice. - No.
我同意
Yes.
[咒语]
小萨姆
Sammy!
- 迪恩 - 小萨姆
- Dean! - Sammy!
我能感觉到他
I can feel him.
- 天哪 - 你得尽快跳进去
- Oh, God! - You got to go now!
起来
Come on!
快 小萨姆
Go now, Sammy.
快
Now!
我逗你呢
I was just messing with you.
小萨姆早不在了
Sammy's long gone.
[咒语]
我说过的
I told you…
会有这一天的 在底特律
This would always happen in Detroit.
萨姆
Sam.
别闹了
Come on.
我都能感觉到
I can feel you…
你在里面折腾呢
Scratching away in there.
这样
Look…
我让你说话 好不好
I'll take the gag off, okay?
孩子 你误会我了
You got me all wrong, kiddo.
我不是坏人
I'm not the bad guy here.
我要从里面把你撕成碎片
I'm gonna rip you apart from the inside out.
你明白吗
Do you understand me?
你为何如此愤怒
Such anger…
年轻的天行者
young Skywalker.
你到底是生谁的气
Who are you really angry with?
是我
Me?
还你自己
Or that face in the mirror?
我知道 这对你而言就是个笑话
I'm sure this is all a big joke to you, huh?
也不尽然
Not at all.
我一直在等你
I've been waiting for you…
等了很久很久
for a long, long time.
萨姆 别这样
Come on, Sam.
你必须承认
You have to admit …
你也感觉得到吧
you can feel it, right?
什么
What?
难以抑制的兴奋
The exhilaration.
你知道这是为什么
And you know why that is?
因为我们终于合二为一
Because we're two halves made whole.
天造地设的一对
M.F.E.O.
简直没有之一
Literally.
别睁着眼说瞎话
This feels pretty damn far from good.
萨姆 我就在你体内
I'm inside your grapefruit, Sam.
你骗不了我
You can't lie to me.
我看得一清二楚
I see it all …
你觉得自己是个怪物
how odd you always felt,
你觉得自己与家人
How…out of place.
是多么格格不入
in that… family of yours.
你何必要忍受这种家庭呢
And why shouldn't you have?
他们最多算是抚养你长大而已
They were foster care … at best.
我才是你真正的家人
I'm your real family.
不 不是
No, that's not true.
就是
It is.
我知道你很清楚这一点
And I know you know it.
你一直在逃避
All those times you ran away,
你不是想逃避他们
you weren't running from them.
而是想来寻找我
You were running towards me.
要知道这并不算坏事
This doesn't have to be a bad thing, you know.
我没有杀死迪恩对吧
I let Dean live, didn't I?
我不想让他死
I want him to live.
我也会带回你的亲朋好友
I'll bring your folks back, too.
萨姆 我想让你快乐
I want you to be happy, Sam.
你的一切我都不稀罕
I don't want anything from you…
真的吗
Really?
一点回报都不求吗
Not even a little payback?
你什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
仔细看看
Look closely.
这些恶魔 看着眼熟吧
None of these little devils look familiar to you?
这是本斯曼先生
That's Mr. Bensman…
是我的小学老师
one of my grade-school teachers.
那个叫道格的 是你在东兰辛市的朋友
And that's your friend Doug from that time in East Lansing.
还有蕾切尔
And Rachel…
是你的舞伴
your prom date.
萨姆·温彻斯特 这就是你的生活历程
Sam Winchester, this is your life.
阿撒兹勒那一伙人
Azazel's gang …
在你还是婴儿的时候就盯上了你
watching you since you were a rugrat,
把你像狗一样耍的团团转
Jerking you around like a dog on a leash.
我知道你对他们的感觉
I know how you feel about them.
我的感觉和你一样
Me too.
你觉得我们联手发泄发泄怎么样
So, what do you say you and I blow off a little steam?
铺天盖地的灾难报道
Reports are flooding in …
波特兰发生了7.6级地震
a 7.6 earthquake in Portland,
波士顿发生8.1级地震
8.1 in Boston,
香港 柏林 德黑兰也发生了地震
More in Hong Kong, Berlin, and Tehran.
美国地质勘探局对此没有任何解释
The U.S.G.S. has no explanation.
只透露死亡人数可能达到六位数
but says to expect a six-figure death toll.
开始了
It's starting.
是吗 天才
Yeah, you think, genius?
没必要这么刻薄吧
You don't have to be mean.
我们现在怎么办
what do we do now?
我建议去喝点小酒 寻点小乐
I suggest we imbibe copious quantities of alcohol…
乖乖等着这一场无法避免的灾难
Just wait for the inevitable blast wave.
谢谢你 大诗人
Yes, well. Thank you, Bukowski.
我是说 我们怎么阻止这一切
I-I mean, how do we stop it?
我们不用阻止
We don't.
路西法会和米迦勒在特定地点会面
Lucifer will meet Michael on the chosen field,
然后便是世界末日
and the battle of armageddon begins.
好吧 那是在哪儿
Okay, well, where's this chosen field?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们总得做点什么
Well, there's got to be something that we can do.
抱歉 迪恩 这一切已成定局
I'm sorry, Dean. This is over.
你给我听着 没出息的娘们
You listen to me, you junklessisissy …
我们绝不放弃
We are not giving up!
鲍比
Bobby?
我们本来就没什么希望
There was never much hope to begin with.
我不知道还能做什么
I don't know what else to do.
那么
So…
玩够没有
Are we having fun yet?
在工作的闲暇
In between jobs,
萨姆和迪恩有时会抽出一天
Sam and Dean would sometimes get a day …
有时运气够好 就有一周
sometimes a week, if they were lucky.
他们会去发点小财 顺利打发时间
They'd pass the time lining their pockets.
萨姆曾坚持用正当手段赚钱
Sam used to insist on honest work,
但现在也赌博骗钱 和哥哥学坏了
But now he hustles pool, like his brother.
他们能随心所欲地去任何地方
They could go anywhere and do anything.
他们可以开上1千英里去看场黑色安息日的演唱会
They drove 1, 000 miles for an ozzy show,
开个两天去看场堪萨斯松鹰队的比赛
Two days for a jayhawks game.
当天气晴朗时
And when it was clear,
他们就把车停在路边
They parker in the middle of nowhere,
坐在车盖上看星星
Sit on the hood, and watch the stars…
一看就是几个小时
For hours…
彼此之间相顾无言
Without saying a word.
他们当然不会想到
It never occurred to them that, sure,
他们可能没机会有间真正的房子
maybe they never really had a roof and four walls,
但其实他们从来都不曾无家可归
But they were never, in fact, homeless.
这句写得有感觉
That's a good line.
是麦妲小姐吗
Mistress Magda?
不 不是 恰克
Um, no, Chuck.
噢 迪恩
Oh, uh, Dean.
没想到是你打来的
Uh, wow. I, uh, I didn't know that you'd call.
麦妲小姐是谁
Who's mistress Magda?
没什么 她是…
Nothing. She's a, uh, a …
只是个亲密的朋友罢了
Just a, uh… A close friend.
好吧 肯定不是一点点亲密
Yeah, I'll bet … real close.
你和贝基怎么了
Whatever happened to Becky?
处得不怎么好
Didn't work out.
我太迁就她了
I had too much respect for her.
小子 你正在召妓是吧
Boy, you really got a whole virgin/hooker thing going on, don't you?
得 你不是为这事打电话的吧
Okay, this can't be why you called.
萨姆答应了路西法
Sam said yes.
我知道
I know.
我预见到了
I saw it.
我刚刚正写到那里
I'm just working on the pages.
你知道最后一战是在哪里吗
Did you see where the title fight goes down?
天使们把它作为最高机密
The angels are keeping it top secret …
非常隐秘
Very hush-hush.
可恶
Aw, crap.
但是我还是看到了
But I saw it anyway.
这是先知的特权
Perks of being a prophet.
明天正午
It's tomorrow, high noon …
一个叫斯塔尔墓地的地方
Place called Stull Cemetery.
斯塔尔墓…
Stull ceme…
等等 我知道这个地方
Wait. I know that.
是在劳伦斯郊外的一个古老墓地
That's … that's an old boneyard outside of Lawrence.
为什么在劳伦斯
Why Lawrence?
我不知道
I don't know.
万事总得有始有终吧
It all has to end where it started, I guess.
好吧 恰克 听着
All right, Chuck, look,
你知道有其他解决方法吗
You know of any way to short-circuit this thing?
除了用那些戒指
Besides the rings?
没有 对不起
No. I'm sorry.
那你知道接下来会发生什么吗
Well, do you have any idea what's gonna happen next?
我也想知道
I wish that I did.
但目前为止 我真的不知道
But I-I just … I honestly don't know yet.
好吧 谢谢 恰克
All right. Thanks, chuck.
你要去哪儿
You goin' someplace?
是去干蠢事吧
You're goin' to do somethin' stupid.
都写你脸上了
You got that look.
我要去和萨姆谈谈
I'm gonna go talk to Sam.
你怎么就是不放弃呢
You just don't give up.
他是我弟弟
It's Sam!
如果你在这里都唤不醒他
If you couldn't reach him here,
那在战场上就更唤不醒他
You're certainly not gonna be able to on the battlefield.
反正我们都已经输了
Well, if we've already lost,
我也没什么可顾虑了吧
I guess I got nothing to lose, right?
我只是想提醒你
I just want you to understand …
即使你去了也无能为力
The only thing that you're gonna see out there.
只能眼睁睁看着米迦勒杀死你弟弟
Is michael killing your brother.
那我也要陪他一起死
Well, then I ain't gonna let him die alone.
见到你真高兴 米迦勒
It's good to see you, michael.
我也是
You too.
我等待这一刻已多时
It's been too long.
终于走到这一步 真是激动人心
Can you believe it's finally here?
不
No.
我没什么感觉
Not really.
你准备好了吗
Are you ready?
早就蓄势待发
As I'll ever be.
我心里还有个声音在阻止我
A part of me wishes we didn't have to do this.
是的
Yeah.
我和你一样
Me too.
那为什么还要如此
Then why are we?
你心里清楚
Oh, you know why.
经过你的所作所为 我已别无选择
I have no choice, after what you did.
我又做了什么
What I did?
那根本不是我的错
What if it's not my fault?
这是什么意思
What is that supposed to mean?
仔细想想
Think about it.
父亲创造了一切
Dad made everything.
也是他造就了我
Which means he made me who I am.
他想要恶魔存在
God wanted the devil.
所以呢
So?
那又何必如此
So why?
为何要让我们自相残杀
And why make us fight?
我真是不明白
I just can't figure out the point.
那你想说什么
What's your point?
我们非要拼个你死我活
We're going to kill each other.
这又是何苦
And for what?
就因为是父亲的考验吗
One of dad's tests.
而我们甚至都被蒙在鼓里
And we don't even know the answer.
我们是亲兄弟
We're brothers.
我们没必要再受他摆布
Let's just walk off the chessboard.
很抱歉 我做不到
I'm sorry. I-I can't do that.
我是忠诚的儿子 必须奉命行事
I'm a good son, and I have my orders.
你不必遵守那些命令
But you don't have to follow them.
你这是让我堕天吗
What, you think I'm gonna rebel?
在这种时候
Now?
我和你不一样
I'm not like you.
求你了 米迦勒
Please, Michael …
弟弟 你真是一点都没变
You know, you haven't changed a bit, little brother.
总是埋怨别人 却从不审视自己
Always blaming everybody but yourself.
我们曾在一起的时光是多么快乐
We were together. We were happy.
但你却背叛了我 我们大家
But you betrayed me … all of us …
甚至逼走了我们的父亲
and you made our father leave.
没人逼迫他
No one makes dad do anything.
是他如此对待我们
He is doing this to us.
路西法 你是个恶魔
You're a monster, Lucifer.
我必须杀了你
And I have to kill you.
如果非要如此
If that's the way it's got to be…
那你就来试试吧
…then I'd like to see you try.
伙计们 好啊
Howdy, boys.
抱歉 打扰你们了吗
Sorry. Am I interrupting something?
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
迪恩
Dean.
尽管你一直都很蠢
Even for you,
但跑来这里 还真是蠢到家了
this is a whole new mountain of stupid.
我没空理你 我正和萨姆说话呢
I'm not talking to you. I'm talking to Sam.
迪恩 我已不再需要你
You're no longer the vessel, Dean.
你没资格来这儿
You got no right to be here.
亚当 如果你听得到的话 我很抱歉
Adam, if you're in there somewhere, I am so sorry.
亚当现在不在
Adam isn't home right now.
木鱼脑袋 我回头再来找你
Well, then you're next on my list, buttercup.
现在 我得先跟他算账
But right now, I need five minutes with him.
你这恶心人的蛆虫
You little maggot.
这里没你什么事
You are no longer a part of this story!
嘿 小屁屁
Hey, ass-butt!
有毛搞错 小屁屁
"Ass-butt"?
他很快就会回来 到时估计气疯了
He'll be back … and upset …
但好歹为你争取了点时间
But you got your five minutes.
卡西迪奥
Castiel.
你刚是用圣火驱逐了我兄弟吗
Did you just Molotov my brother with holy fire?
不是吧
Uh…no.
除了我 没人能动米迦勒
No one dicks with Michael but me.
小萨姆 听得见我说话吗
Sammy, can you hear me?
告诉你
You know…
看在小萨姆面上
I tried to be nice…
我对你一直很温柔
for Sammy's sake.
但你
But you…
真是我的眼中钉
are such a pain…
肉中刺
in my ass.
不要
N-o-o-o-o!
没用的
Yes.
小萨姆
Sammy?
你在吗
Are you in there?
他是在 没错
Oh, he's in here, all right.
他还要亲自打得你体无完肤
And he's gonna feel the snap of your bones.
绝不放过你
Every single one.
咱们慢慢来
We're gonna take our time.
萨姆 没关系
Sam, it's okay.
有我在 没事的
It's okay. I'm here.
有我陪你
I'm here.
我不会离开你
I'm not gonna leave you.
我永远都不会离开你
I'm not gonna ave you.
迪恩 没事了
It's okay, Dean.
现在没事了
It's gonna be okay.
我控制住他了
I've got him.
[咒语]
萨姆
Sam!
事情不该发展至此
It's not gonna end this way!
快回来
Step back!
不要阻止我
You're gonna have to make me!
我必须和我哥哥战斗 萨姆
I have to fight my brother, Sam!
就在此时此地
Here and now!
这是我的宿命
It's my destiny!
卡西 你还活着
Cass, you're alive?
比那还好
I'm better than that.
卡西 你是上帝吗
Cass, are you god?
这恭维真不错
That's a nice compliment.
但答案是不
But no.
但我还是相信是他复活了我
Although, I do believe he brought me back.
使我焕然一新
New and improved.
结局总是很难
Endings are hard.
开头很容易 有个键盘
Any chapped-ass monkey with a keyboard.
无知脑残也能办到 但结局却非如此
can poop out a beginning, but endings are impossible.
你越想面面俱到
You try to tie up every loose end,
就越是事与愿违
But you never can.
粉丝都是群欲求不满的婊子
The fans are always gonna bitch.
总会给你找些碴儿
There's always gonna be holes.
既然这都是结局了
And since it's the ending,
那我也就无所畏惧了
It's all supposed to add up to something.
我要告诉你们 让他们折腾去吧
I'm telling you, they're a raging pain in the ass.
你现在打算干嘛
What are you gonna do now?
回天堂吧 我想
Return to heaven, I suppose.
天堂
Heaven?
鉴于米迦勒也被关进了牢笼
With Michael in the cage,
想必现在那儿正群龙无首吧
I'm sure it's total anarchy up there.
怎么 那你成了新头目了吗
So, what, you're the new sheriff in town?
但愿如此 是的 我希望会是我
I like that. Yeah. I suppose I am.
上帝就赐了你一对全新而又闪亮的翅膀
God gives you a brand-new, shiny set of wings,
于是你又立马跪倒在他裤脚下了
And suddenly you're his bitch again.
我不知道上帝有何目的
I don't know what god wants.
也不知道他是否会回来
I don't know if he'll even return.
只是觉得现在就该这么做
It just…Seems like the right thing to do.
好吧 要是你真见到他
Well, if you do see him,
告诉他 接下来我跟他没完
You tell him I'm coming for him next.
你生气了
You're angry.
那还算是温柔的说法
That's an understatement.
他有出手帮过忙
He helped.
只是你没意识到而已
Maybe even more than we realize.
你说得倒容易 因为他把你带回来了
That's easy for you to say. He brought you back.
但是萨姆呢
But what about sam?
我呢
What about me, huh?
我得到了什么好处
Where's my grand prize?
只有我的弟弟被封印
All I got is my brother in a hole!
这正是你想要的 迪恩
You got what you asked for, Dean.
没有天堂 也没有地狱
No paradise. No hell.
只不过是一切照旧
Just more of the same.
我说真的 迪恩
I mean it, Dean.
你究竟想要什么呢
What would you rather have?
宁静还是自由呢
Peace or freedom?
真是 说句再见会死吗
Well, you really suck at goodbyes, you know that?
在那之后 迪恩和鲍比将会分别很长时间
This is the last Dean and Bobby will see of each other for a very long time.
为了强调一下 从现在起再过一周
And, for the record, at this point next week,
鲍比将在代顿城外猎杀一个食人怪
Bobby will be hunting a rugaru outside of Dayton.
但迪恩没有去
But not Dean.
迪恩并不想卡西救他
Dean didn't want Cass to save him.
他浑身上下每寸肌肤
Every part of him, every fiber he's got,
都无不想要寻死
Wants to die.
或是想办法找回萨姆
Or find a way to bring Sam back.
但他不能那么做
But he isn't gonna do either.
因为他对萨姆承诺过
Because he made a promise.
你好 莉莎
Hey, Lisa.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank god.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
没事
Yeah.
如果还不太晚的话 我…
Uh, if it's not too late, I…
那天你要请我喝的啤酒还作数吗
Think I'd like to take you up on that beer.
永远都不晚
It's never too late.
没事了 迪恩
It's okay. Dean.
一切都会好起来
It's gonna be okay.
那接下来会怎样呢
So, what's it all add up to?
很难说
It's hard to say.
但要我说这只个考验
But me, I'd say this was a test…
对萨姆和迪恩的考验
For Sam and Dean.
我觉得他俩干得不错
And I think they did all right.
与正邪善恶打交道
Up against good, evil,
遭遇天使恶魔 面对宿命 还有上帝本尊
Angels, devils, destiny, and god himself,
他们自己做出了选择
They made their own choice.
他们选择了家庭
They chose family.
而这
And, well…
不正是重中之重吗
Isn't that kinda the whole point?
（完结）
毫无疑问 事到最终总难以放手
No doubt … endings are hard.
但话说回来
But then again…
没什么会真正到头吧
Nothing ever really ends, does it?
你没事吧
You okay?
没事 我挺好的
Yeah, I'm good.